Guide to the Harry Shulman Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harry Shulman papers
1922-1955
MS 239
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
(24 boxes)
The papers consist of professional correspondence, writings and files documenting Harry Shulman's work as an arbitrator in labor-management disputes. Included here are the records for some thirty cases over which he presided (1942-1955). Shulman's general files record his occasional practice of private law, his teaching at Yale Law School and contain an essay written in 1929 while he was a law clerk to Louis D. Brandeis. The correspondence contains a large number of letters congratulating Shulman on his appointment as Dean of the Yale Law School in 1954, some reflecting on the controversy over his being the first Jew to achieve that position. Among his writings are the manuscripts of several chapters on legal and labor subjects, possibly intended for an unpublished book.
Shulman, Harry, 1903-1955
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephen N. Shulman, 1981-1982.
Scope and Contents
The Harry Shulman Papers consist of twenty-four boxes and are divided into four series, CORRESPONDENCE, ARBITRATION, SUBJECT FILES, and WRITINGS. The collection was transferred to the Yale University Library in 1981 and 1982 by Stephen N. Shulman, son of the Yale Law School Dean.
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, is housed in Boxes 1-4, folders 1-115. It primarily contains letters to and from Harry Shulman by teaching faculty, persons concerned with the arbitration of labor-management disputes, former students, and professional colleagues. The great majority of correspondence concerns one of the following subjects: messages of congratulations on Shulman's appointment as dean of Yale Law School, letters on his work between 1936 and 1939 on the restatement of the Law of Torts for the American Law Institute, correspondence on the subject of arbitration, and letters on other professional matters.
In January 1954, Yale President A. Whitney Griswold chose Shulman dean of Yale Law School to succeed Wesley A. Sturgis. This appointment was an extremely popular one and Shulman was flooded with scores of letters from former students, academic colleagues, arbitration associates, and friends. Letters also poured in from leaders in the Yale community, law school faculty, and lawyers from throughout the country. Shulman's appointment was also, however, a controversial one, for he was the first identifying Jew to be selected a Yale dean. This subject is only alluded to in letters from Lloyd N. Cutler, William Delano, Felix Frankfurter, Richard M. Haber, and Wilmarth S. Lewis. Those who opposed Shulman cloaked their opposition by asserting that an "outside man" or "fresh blood" was needed to reinvigorate the Law School. As Felix Frankfurter stated in a letter probably written near the end of 1953, "you can't escape the fact that your selection as Dean would be a decisive triumph for 'civilized' conduct in realms where even the best institutions are at best laggards and too often woefully backward." Wilmarth S. Lewis affirmed that,
"In my sixteen years on the Corporation I have never heard such enviable statements made by so many people whose good opinion one would hope to have as were made on your behalf. If it is characteristic of our frightened time that your appointment should have caused excessive discussion, I think it is also a heartening sign of healthiness of present-day Yale that you now have what you should have had years ago."
Shulman received congratulatory messages from many well known people, including Mrs. James Rowland Angell, James T. Babb, Milton Conover, Gerald R. Ford, Jr., Jerome Frank, Arthur J. Goldberg, Erwin E. Griswold, Walter P. Reuther, Peter Seitz, Potter Stewart, and Henry M. Wriston.
In 1936, Shulman succeeded the ill Francis H. Bohlen as the American Law Institute reporter for the restatement of the Law of Torts. This task took three years and Shulman corresponded extensively with William Draper Lewis, director of the American Law Institute, Anna M. Judge, executive secretary to the director, and a large number of legal scholars, like Francis H. Bohlen, Oliver W. Branch, Walter J. Derenberg, Laurence H. Eldredge, Herbert F. Goodrich, Milton Handler, Edmund M. Morgan, T. Scott Orfutt, and Warren A. Seavey.
Harry Shulman was best known outside the Yale community as an arbitrator in labor-management disputes. From 1943 until his death, he was impartial umpire for the Ford Motor Company, and the United Auto Workers, C.I O. He was also administrative associate member and director of dispute for the National War Labor Board, was a member of the Wage Stabilization Board during the Korean War, was arbitrator for the Bendix Aviation Corporation and Wright Aeronautical Corporation, and was chairman of the panel in the steel industry dispute. Series I contains some arbitration correspondence, but the bulk of this material is found in Series II, ARBITRATION.
In addition, the series includes the usual professional letters of recommendation, correspondence regarding professional meetings, and others of a similar nature. Shulman served for many years as faculty advisor to the Yale Law Journal, a task that sometimes involved him in disputes between the editor and potential contributors over manuscripts submitted to the Journal. A 1938 controversy involved editor Lloyd W. Cutler, Carol Agger, and Abe Fortas. In a second 1954 dispute, the parties were editor Richard A. Siegel, A. L. Shalowitz, and Rear Admiral R. F. A. Studds.
The collection contains relatively little personal correspondence. The letters of Max Turner, folders 101-103, covering the years 1925-1933, form the only significant group of personal letters. They chronicle Turner's struggles as a young New York City lawyer. Shulman correspondend with a large number of legal scholars, law school faculty, people involved in arbitration, and former students. Prominent correspondents include Dean Acheson, Louis D. Brandeis, Felix Frankfurter, Learned Hand, Harold J. Laski, William Draper Lewis, and George W. Taylor.
Series II, ARBITRATION, is housed in Boxes 5-13, folders 116-214. It documents Harry Shulman's arbitration/umpire work. Shulman was widely known as an arbitrator in labor-management-disputes, an activity that commenced in 1940 and continued until his death. Files covering this work for twenty-six companies, the Connecticut Labor Relations Board, and the Steel Panel of the Wage Stabilization Board are found in this series. The largest amount of material documents his arbitration/umpire work for Bendix Aviation Corporation (folders 118-155), Borg-Warner Corporation (folders 156-153), Ford Motor Company (folders 178-189), R H. Macy & Company, Inc. (folders 194-199), and Wright Aeronautical Corporation (folders 216-224).
Harry Shulman's fame as an arbitrator arose from a number of factors; his common sense, even temperament, good humor, and exceptional judgment. One particularly well known Shulman story is recounted by Nelle Van D. Smith in chapter twelve of Human Relations: Labor and Management (Box 22, folder 293).
"His expert touch was apparent when a woman worker at a Ford plant was docked a half hour's pay because it was claimed she was distracting workers by her bright red clothing. In deciding for the woman, Shulman reasoned that the company was wrong, since it did not object to bright green slacks, though it was common knowledge that wolves, unlike bulls, may be attracted by colors other than red, and by various other enticements in the art and fit of female clothes."
Series III is composed of SUBJECT FILES and fills Boxes 14-22, folders 225-304. Harvard Law School Notes make up the largest amount of material, Boxes 17-20. Harry Shulman did not practice law extensively, and the collection contains relatively little on this aspect of his career. He was receiver for the bankrupt furrier company of Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman (folders 253-259) in 1928-1929 and was one of the legal representatives of the Manhattan Railway Company in the IRT Receivership case of 1932-1934 (folders 241-244). In 1929-1930, Shulman was law clerk to Justice Louis D. Brandeis, but only a "Survey Supreme Court October Term 1929" (folder 302) documents this part of his life. Series III also contains copies of seven papers written by Shulman's law school students (folders 295-301); a folder on the 1954 loyalty investigation of Myer Cohen (folder 231); material on his 1923 application for a fellowship from the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace (folder 230); a series of broadsides and other documents on the 1947 struggle between the International Union of Mine Mill and, Smelter-Workers, C.I.O. and the Provisional Metalworkers Council, Industrial Union of Shipbuilding Workers of America, C.I.O. to organize the workers of American Brass Company in Waterbury (folders 246-248); and a variety of materials reflecting Shulman's interest in arbitration (folders 226, 249-252, 261-262, 294).
Series IV, WRITINGS, contains copies of many of his publications, but not copies of his major books, and manuscripts of several chapters of a possibly unpublished book. These materials are found in Boxes 24-25.
Several aspects of the life and career of Harry Shulman are inadequately covered in the Harry Shulman Papers. The collection contains no family correspondence and little to document his personal life. The bulk of the correspondence covers the years 1936-1939 and 1952-1954. In addition, the papers contain almost nothing on Shulman's long teaching career at Yale, and, likewise, virtually nothing on Yale prejudice against Jewish faculty members. The Harry Shulman Papers, then, are most useful to those interested in the arbitration of labor-management disputes.
Biographical / Historical
Lawyer; born in Russia in 1903; came to the U.S., 1912; B.A., Brown, 1923; LL.B., Harvard Law School, 1926, S.J.D., 1927; in 1929 he left the practice of law in New York City to serve as law clerk to Justice Brandeis; in 1930 he came to Yale Law School as an instructor, and was subsequently made Assistant Professor of Law, 1931, Associate Professor, 1933, Professor. 1937, Lines Professor, 1939, and Sterling Professor, 1940; made Dean of Law School, 1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arbitration, Industrial; Jews -- United States; Labor disputes; Labor laws and legislation; Law -- Study and teaching; Law; Lawyers; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Branch, Oliver Winslow, b. 1879; Derenberg, Walter J., 1903-1975; Eldredge, Laurence H. (Laurence Howard), 1902-1982; Finkelstein, Louis, 1895-1991; Fortas, Abe, 1910-1982; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Fulda, Carl H., 1909-; Goldberg, Arthur J., 1908-; Goodrich, Herbert F. (Herbert Funk), 1889-1962; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961; Handler, Milton, 1903-1998; Judge, Anna M.; Lewis, William Draper, 1867-1949; Morgan, Edmund Morris, 1878-1966; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Seavey, Warren Abner, 1880-1966; Shulman, Harry, 1903-1955; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Turner, Max; Warburg, James P. (James Paul), 1896-1969; Yale Law School
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1925-1955; Series I; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  CORRESPONDENCE contains letters written to Harry Shulman from professional colleagues, friends, and former students plus carbons of many of Shulman's own letters. All correspondence is arranged alphabetically by surname of the correspondent and then chronologically. Undated letters follow dated ones and unidentified correspondence is placed last in Box 4, folder 115.
  As a general rule, there must be at least four letters to or from a correspondent for a separate listing, although there are some exceptions e.g. separate listings are given for the letters from Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Harry Truman. In other cases one to three letters to and from an individual are filed alphabetically with the first letter of the surname. Those looking therefore, for letters from persons that are unlisted should examine the appropriate letter file.
  Folders with asterisks (*) contain ten or more items.
  - 'A' general, 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aaron, Benjamin, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Dean G., 1940-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adler, Jerome H., 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Austern, H. Thomas, 1930-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 'B' general, 1931-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Bikle, Henry Wolf, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bohlen, Francis H., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Branch, Oliver W. (*), 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brandeis, Alice, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brandeis, Louis D., 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 'C' general, 1931-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Clark, Charles E., 1931, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Crane, Newton D., 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cutler, Lloyd N., 1938, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 'D' general, 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Derenberg, Walter J. (*), 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 'E' general, 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Eldredge, Laurence H. (*), 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 'F' general, 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Farrend, George E., 1930-1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Feil, Anthony E., 1951, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fierst, Herbert A., 1940, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fortas, Abe, 1938, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Fraenkel, Osmond K., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Frankfurter, Estelle S., 1938, 1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Frankfurter, Marion, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Frankfurter, Felix (*), 1930-1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fulda, Carl H. (*), 1938-1954 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 'G' general, 1938-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gilpatric, Roswell L., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Goodrich, Herbert F. (*), 1838-1854 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Griswold, Erwin N., 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 'H' general, 1930-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
  - Hadley, Arlene, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hand, Learned, 1938-1954 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Handler, Milton (*), 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hardman, Thomas P., 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Holden, Reuben A., 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Holtzmann, Howard M., 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Horowitz, Samuel B., 1954 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Howard, Charles McH., 1939 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 'J' general, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Jackson, Elmore, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    General
    See also: box 16, folders 261-62
  - Jaegerman, Edward C., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Judge, Anna M. (*), 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 49-51)
  - 'K' general, 1931-1954 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Kessler, Friedrich, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 'L' general, 1930-1954 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lance, Saul J., 1931-1954 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Laski, Harold J., 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Latimer, Murray W., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lawson, William E., 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Levert, Albert M., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Levy, Melvin, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Lewis, William Draper (*), 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 61-64)
  - 'M' general, 1931-1954 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - McAleer, James J., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - MacLean, J. A., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Madden, J. Warren, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Mathews, Robert E.
    See: box 14, folder 232
  - Meck, John Foster, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Moreel, Ben, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Morgan, Edmund M. (*), 1938-1954 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - 'N' general, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Nichol, Thomas, Jr., 1938, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Nims, Harry D., 1932-1954 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - 'O' general, 1932-1954 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Offutt, T. Scott, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Oppenheim, S. Chesterfield, 1938, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Ormsby, Robert, 1951, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - 'P' general, 1937-1954 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Pound, Roscoe, 1937, 1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Quigley, Thomas J., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - 'R' general, 1931-1954 (Box 3, Folder 82-83)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Rourke, Joseph M., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Rugg, Charles B., 1951-1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - 'S' general, 1937-1954 (Box 3, Folder 87-88)
  - Scully, Edward N., 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Seavey, Warren A. (*), 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Severn, Marion L., 1938 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Shalowitz, A. L., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Smith, Russell A., 1952, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Stafford, William W., 1938, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Strock, Alan M., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - 'T' general, 1938-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 96-97)
  - Taylor, George W., 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Tebbe, Carl G., 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Truman, Harry, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Turner, Max (*), 1925-1933, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 101-103)
  - 'U' general, 1937-1954 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - 'V' general, 1938, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Van Hecke, M. T., 1938 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - 'W' general, 1931-1954 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Warburg, James P., 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Warshaw, Melvin, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Wriston, Henry M., 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr., 1938-1954 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - 'Y' general, 1930-1954 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - 'Z' general, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Zuckert, Eugene M., 1938, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Unidentified, 1937-1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 115)
- ARBITRATION, 1940-1955; Series II; 3.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
  Series II ARBITRATION, contains case files documenting Harry Shulman's extensive work as an arbitrator and umpire. The files are arranged alphabetically, mostly by name of corporation. The folders are roughly sorted by date, but no attempt has been made to place everything in its proper chronological order, A file typically includes briefs by both parties in a dispute, copies of decisions rendered, often correspondence relating to the cases, and other similar documentation.
  - Aviation Corporation of America, Republic Aircraft Products Division, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 116-117)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Bendix Products Division, 1942-1951 (Box 5, Folder 118-128)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Bendix Products Division, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 129-131)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Eclipse Machine Division, 1951-1953 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Eclipse Pioneer Division, 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 133-143)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Eclipse Pioneer Division, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 144-148)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Owosso Division, 1940-1943 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Skinner Purifiers Division, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Wayne Division, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Bendix Aviation Corporation, Zenith Carburetor Division, 1946-1953 (Box 7, Folder 152-155)
  - Borg-Warner Corporation, Warner Gear Division, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 156-163)
  - Campbell Soup Company, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Capital Transit Company, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Commonwealth Industries, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Connecticut, State of: Labor Relations Board, 1945-1946 (Box 9, Folder 167-174)
  - Cushman Chuck Company, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - Dictaphone Corporation, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Fairchild Engine & Aircraft Corporation, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 178)
  - Ford Motor Company: Opinions of the Umpire, A-1-A-284, 1943-1954 (Box 9, Folder 178-180)
  - Ford Motor Company: Umpire Memorandum Decisions, 1-2627, 1943-1955 (Box 10, Folder 181-189)
  - Hartford Wire Works Company, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 190)
  - Household Fuel Corporation, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 191)
  - John A. Roebling's Sons Co., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 192)
  - Lesnow Brothers, Inc., undated (Box 10, Folder 193)
  - Macy (R.H.) & Company, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 194-199)
  - Manning, Maxwell & Moore, Inc., 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 200)
  - Marlin-Rockwell Corporation, 1939-1941 (Box 11, Folder 201-202)
  - The Mattatuck Manufacturing Company, 1951, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - Narragansett Brewing Co. and The James Hanley Co., 1946 (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - New Jersey Bell Telephone Company, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - The New York Times, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 206)
  - North American Aviation, Inc., 1945 (Box 11, Folder 207)
  - The Rockbestos Corporation, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 208)
  - Singer Manufacturing Company, 1947-1951 (Box 12, Folder 209-210)
  - Steel Panel, Wage Stabilization Board, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 211-213)
  - Talon, Inc., 1953 (Box 12, Folder 214)
  - United Engineering Co., Ltd., 1945 (Box 12, Folder 215)
  - Wright Aeronautical Corporation, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 216-218)
  - Wright Aeronautical Corporation, 1944-1953 (Box 13, Folder 219-224)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1922-1955; Series III; 4 linear feet (9 boxes)
  The materials in Series III are arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically. In addition to containing material that documents Shulman's professional interests, the SUBJECT FILES also include four boxes of law school notes.
  - Alien cases, summaries of, undated (Box 14, Folder 225)
  - American Arbitration Association, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 226)
    See also:box 15, folder 252,
  - American Law Institute, 1941-1943 (Box 14, Folder 227)
  - American Law Institute: program, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 228)
  - American Law Institute: trade marks, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 229)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: Notes, drafts, etc., 1923, undated (Box 14, Folder 230)
  - Cohen, Myer: loyalty investigation of, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 231)
  - Conference on Training of Law Students in Labor Relations, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 232)
  - Connecticut, State of: Department of Labor and Factory Inspection, Minimum Wage Division, 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 233-234)
  - Connecticut, State of: Mercantile Wage Board, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 235)
  - Consumers' Advisory Board, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 236)
  - Harvard graduation program, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 237)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association: membership directory, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 238)
  - Industrial Relations Research Association: Membership directory, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 239)
  - International Congress of Comparative Law, 1931-1932 (Box 15, Folder 240)
  - IRT receivership, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 241-242)
  - IRT receivership: correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 15, Folder 243)
  - IRT receivership: newspaper clippings, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 244)
  - Labor relations: bibliography, 1947,undated (Box 15, Folder 245)
  - Mine-Mill Withdrawal Dispute, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 246-248)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators, 1947, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 250)
  - National War Labor Board, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 251)
  - The New York Times--Newspaper Guild negotiations, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 252)
  - Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman: bills, receipts, etc., 1925-1929 (Box 15, Folder 253-254)
  - Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman: correspondence, 1928 November-1929 January (Box 15, Folder 255)
  - Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman: correspondence, 1929 February-March1930 March (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman: insurance policies and agreements, 1922-1928 (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - Ostrow, Pochoda, and Gorman: legal documents, 1928-1930 (Box 16, Folder 258-259)
  - Palestine Economic Corporation, 1931-1936, undated (Box 16, Folder 260)
  - Quaker House (American Friends Service Committee), 1949-1950, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 261-262)
  - Record of the Fellows of Davenport College, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 263)
  - Retail Wage Board, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 264)
  - Shulman, Harry: law school note cards, undated (Box 17)